<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Surbhi Sharma</title><link>https://ssurbhi560.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Surbhi Sharma</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ssurbhi560.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Outreachy Final wrap-up blog</title><link>https://ssurbhi560.github.io/blogs/outreachy-final-wrap-up-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssurbhi560.github.io/blogs/outreachy-final-wrap-up-blog/</guid><description>This blog is about my work during my Outreachy internship with conda-forge. Before that a little about me - I am Surbhi, an outreachy intern with conda-forge for the May-August 2022 cohort. I worked on documenting the conda-forge ecosystem.
The first issue I started working on when the internship began was Better anchoring of announcements(#1611). The goal of this issue was to fix the anchor for each year and also specific announcements in the Announcements section so as to provide better navigation of the Announcements page.</description></item><item><title>Outreachy mid-point project progress.</title><link>https://ssurbhi560.github.io/blogs/outreachy-mid-point-progress/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssurbhi560.github.io/blogs/outreachy-mid-point-progress/</guid><description>This week marked the mid-point of my internship at conda-forge as an Outreachy intern. I am working on documenting the conda-forge ecosystem. In this blog, I will go through the work progress I have been able to make so far, goals for the coming weeks, and some of the (many) things I have learned so far.
The first issue I started working on when the internship began was Better anchoring of announcements.</description></item><item><title>Outreachy - Everybody Struggles</title><link>https://ssurbhi560.github.io/blogs/outreachy-blog-everybody-struggles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssurbhi560.github.io/blogs/outreachy-blog-everybody-struggles/</guid><description>This is the second blog post in the series of Outreachy internship blogs I am writing. The topic for this one is to write about something we are struggling with right now. With the work I have been doing for my project, there isn&amp;rsquo;t anything I am struggling with right now. Thanks to my awesome mentors and other wonderful folks at conda-forge, who are always there for help.
The only thing that I am struggling with is writing these blogs.</description></item><item><title>Outreachy - Introduce yourself</title><link>https://ssurbhi560.github.io/blogs/outreachy-blog-introduction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssurbhi560.github.io/blogs/outreachy-blog-introduction/</guid><description>In this blog, I will be sharing about my application journey and my core values.
Although if you have ended up here you might have read about me on this website but, I will still briefly introduce myself:
I am Surbhi, and I recently graduated from college where I completed BSc. (Honours) in Computer Applications after that, I worked at Pravatak Technologies Labs, IIT Madras as Project Associate. I was responsible for building a web application that could serve the voila applications to users after proper authentication.</description></item><item><title>How to setup ZNC bouncer!</title><link>https://ssurbhi560.github.io/blogs/how-to-setup-znc-bouncer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssurbhi560.github.io/blogs/how-to-setup-znc-bouncer/</guid><description>After struggling for so many days today, finally, I could set up the ZNC bouncer. This blog post is about what steps I followed, the silly mistakes I made, and how I solved all of those.
But before proceeding to all that, let&amp;rsquo;s first see what ZNC bouncer is, what IRC is, and why everyone should try and use this awesome communication platform.
So let&amp;rsquo;s get started - IRC is a platform for real-time communication for open source contributors but not just limited to them; and anyone can use it.</description></item><item><title>Types of Programming languages</title><link>https://ssurbhi560.github.io/blogs/types-of-programming-languages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssurbhi560.github.io/blogs/types-of-programming-languages/</guid><description>There is no limit to the number of ways we can classify programming languages. Here, I will be trying to focus on one particular classification which is related to the way of declaration of the constructs in the language.
Let’s start with discussing statically typed language and dynamically typed language.
Before diving in to understand these, first we need know what is type checking? So, let&amp;rsquo;s read about that first.</description></item><item><title>Learnings from The Dip by Seth Godin</title><link>https://ssurbhi560.github.io/blogs/learning-from-the-dip-by-seth-godin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssurbhi560.github.io/blogs/learning-from-the-dip-by-seth-godin/</guid><description>When should you QUIT something?
So, I recently read &amp;lsquo;The Dip&amp;rsquo; by Seth Godin, and this blog is about what I learned from the book.
It&amp;rsquo;s not a long book, and if you are an avid reader, it would hardly take a few hours. It focuses on QUITTING!! A negative word, right?
No! In fact it is an essential thing that everyone should know &amp;lsquo;when&amp;rsquo; to do, if they want to save their precious time, resources and also wants to perform their best in whatever they do.</description></item></channel></rss>